## Like Zheng

Software Engineer

#### **About**

I have 5 years of software development experience, with a strong focus on front-end development. I also have experience in product design, and have dabbled in UX and UI design. I place great emphasis on user experience, which has driven me to learn more about design-related knowledge. I highly value teamwork and have successfully built a 6-person front-end team with an agile culture from scratch.

### Skills



## Experience

ByteArk Tech Ltd.

Aug 2021 - Present

Technical Lead Hangzhou, China | Remote

Participate in Filecoin community interactions and collect and process community information; design and develop applications based on Filecoin and IPFS.

- Managed an agile team of 5 members, including 2 front-end developers, 2 back-end developers, and 1 UI designer.
- Designed and participated in the development of a cloud storage prototype based on Filecoin and IPFS.
- Designed and participated in the development of a Filecoin Remote Sealing Platform (Sealing-as-a-Service).
- Published Filecoin Weekly newsletter (internal), featuring content such as Filecoin-related news, offline events, code updates, articles, and videos. Successfully released 10 issues, with over 200 cumulative views.

Muri Tech Ltd. Mar 2021 - Jul 2021

Front-End Lead Hangzhou, China

Optimized Git workflow and advanced the construction of the front-end design system, which led to an early promotion to Front-End Lead.

Managed a 5-person front-end team responsible for developing and maintaining web applications.

- Implemented a new Git workflow (based on Trunk-Based Development), reducing bugs caused by code conflicts.
- Migrated legacy UmiJS code to NextJS and performed refactoring, optimizing SEO through SSR; reduced package size by 10%; and improved development experience.
- Introduced Directus CMS and NextJS Preview Mode features, reducing backend development workload by 10%;
   streamlined the process for updating copy and images, reducing the time from 1 day to 10 minutes.

"ByteArk Tech Ltd.
Feb 2019 - Feb 2021

Front-End Lead Hangzhou, China

Promoted to Front-End Lead after probation, responsible for formulating front-end standards and architectural design.

- Managed an 8-person front-end team, responsible for developing and maintaining web applications, mobile applications, and WeChat mini-programs.
- Established development processes and standards, including Git workflow guidelines, code Lint rules, code review guides, and front-end design systems.
- Researched agile development methodologies and put them into practice, improving team efficiency and producing over 10,000 words of documentation.

# Ningbo Port Information and Communication Ltd.

Aug 2018 - Jan 2019

Front-End Developer Ningbo, China

Developed and maintained a port declaration system website, using a technology stack of Java and ExtJS.

 Introduced polyfills for grid and flex, ensuring compatibility with IE11 while optimizing the development experience.

### **Projects**

PandaruaAug 2022 - Sep 2022

Project Lead ByteArk Tech Ltd.

Figma Product Map

A Filecoin Remote Sealing (Sealing-as-a-Service) Platform.

 Alleviated the pressure on the underlying computational power supply by managing sectors using resource packs.

MePrint Mar 2021 - Jul 2021

Front-End Lead Muri Tech Ltd.

React NextJS React Query Emotion DirectusCMS

An Al-based clothing pattern design platform.

- Migrated legacy UmiJS code to NextJS and performed refactoring, optimizing SEO through SSR; reduced package size by 10%; and improved development experience.
- Introduced Directus CMS and NextJS Preview Mode features, reducing backend development workload by 10%; streamlined the process for updating copy and images, reducing the time from 1 day to 10 minutes.
- Implemented react-query, reducing the complexity of state management and enhancing both user experience and development experience.

**Dragonfly** Oct 2020 - Nov 2020

1/410	Nodo IS	Co	Powergate	IDEC	Lotus
vue	Nouess	GO	rowergate	IFF3	Lotus

A docker image storage service.

- The project won the first prize in the first phase of the Filecoin Slingshot competition.
- Modified Powergate's source code to enable the import of offline transactions into the database.
- Delivered a project presentation at the Closing Ceremony (video link).

 \*Matrix
 Sep 2019 - Jan 2020

 Front-End Lead
 ByteArk Tech Ltd.

Flutter Taro React Fastlane

A mining equipment management system client.

- Built a multi-platform mobile application using Flutter.
- Automated the release process using Fastlane.

**Arc** Sep 2019 - Jan 2020

Front-End Lead ByteArk Tech Ltd.

TypeScript React Rollup Emotion Storybook Jest

A design system focusing on user experience and usability.

- Researched and analyzed over 10 design systems.
- Developed more than 10 components, which have been successfully used in production environments.

#### **Education**

# **University of Guelph**

Sep 2012 - Dec 2017

**Bachelor of Computer Engineering** 

### Languages

Chinese Native speaker English Fluent

https://resume.ekil.io April 19, 2023 at 3:25:22 PM